Fen Xie

xfjoy0223@gmail.com 206.201.4312 http://joyx.design

SUMMARY

Experienced UX/UI designer with over 5-year experience in the tech industry. Coming from a background of engineering and product management, with the goal of designing technology for a wider audience, I design with empathy and deliver with thoughtfulness. Currently working on making big data simple.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer

09/2015-Current

Databricks, Inc, San Francisco, U.S.

- Owned the design and collaborated with product managers and engineers to deliver a wide variety of features.
- Built an online style guide from scratch to improve product consistency and design efficiency. Contributed CSS code to standardized variables and fix styles in product.
- Established and shared a design checklist to ensure a better design process.
- Used our product to analyze surveys and usage data to do data-informed design.

Product Manager

03/2013-11/2013

Opera Software ASA, Beijing, China

- Coordinated 15+ people team and managed the new release of Opera Mini Chinese version for millions of monthly active users.
- Led 10 people team and launched Sphinx, a browser-based game engine in 3 months.

QA Engineer

06/2011-03/2013

Opera Software ASA, Beijing, China

- Developed 5+ Opera speed dial extensions, one of which reached 200,000 downloads.
- Led the outsourcing project of developing 10+ apps for Opera TV Store.
- Presented Opera products in exhibitions and gave speeches at developer conferences.
- Conducted quality assurance work on Opera Desktop, Mobile, and TV Store, including automated testing.

Software Engineer

08/2007-08/2008

Infosys Technologies Limited, Shanghai, China

- Developed banking backend services under Mainframe system using Cobol and DB2.
- Collected and analyzed customer requirements onsite.

EDUCATION

Master of Human-Computer Interaction & Design

09/2014-08/2015

University of Washington, U.S.

Master of Computer Engineering

09/2008-12/2010

Politecnico di Torino, Italy

B.S in Software Engineering

09/2003-07/2007

Huazhong University of Science and Technology, China

SKILLS

Design Methods

User research Prototyping Usability Testing

Design Tools

Sketch Photoshop Illustrator InDesign After Effect

Programming

HTML/CSS/Javascript Python